<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="interior_text">
        The high-tech style is the newest of all. The style in the design of public and residential interiors came into being in the last third of the 20th century. It took its origin from the design of industrial premises. The high-tech style is based on the popularity of science fiction cinema and literature and, of course, the emergence of ultra-modern materials. \n
Characteristics of high-tech style: \n
• minimalism and rationality\n
• cold, light colors\n
• straight lines and angles\n
• lack of ornaments and floral motifs\n
• prevalence of concrete, plastic, glass, metal\n
• the inclusion of pipes, valves, air ducts into the interior\n
• use of metallic colors and finishes with luster\n
• variety of lighting, LED and concealed lighting\n
• plenty of modern technology\n

Venice Bed\n
Although clear shapes and angles dominate, some pieces of furniture and accessories can have smooth, but unusual shapes
        resembling space or technological/industrial style. \n
Use of high-tech style\n
High-tech style is often chosen when a large space is available. But if the room is small, you need to plan the design to
        visually expand the space. That’s why hi-tech style often uses mirrors that “push” the walls. Small, not flat screen TV will look ridiculous in high-tech room. For such space, you need a large LCD/ plasma TV or home cinema. \n
The living room can be combined with home office because any computer and media devices blend harmoniously with the
        high-tech interior. \n

Colors\n
The main colors are cool gray and white. However, bright colors with metallic gloss serve as excellent accents.
        For these purposes use neon green, orange, red and black. \n
Finishing\n
It preferably uses smooth and glossy floor covering: glossy laminate or linoleum, ceramic tiles. \n
Avoid wallpaper with floral motifs, checked and striped patterns. For walls, you can choose plain wallpaper or use
        glossy mirror panels. \n


Furniture\n
Furniture should be glossy, light and laminated. Compact wall units, shelves, TV stands and cabinets with a glossy
        sheen fit well the hi-tech interior. \n
Furniture can be decorated with chrome accents and glass; it may be shelves, coffee tables, TV cabinets, etc. \n
Upholstered furniture has one-color upholstery. It can be a fabric or leather, but preferably smooth and shiny. \n
Chairs or armchairs in the dining room can be plastic, including transparent models. \n
A few pieces of furniture with bizarre shapes will become wonderful decoration of the room. Use unusual and unique chair,
        original coffee table and more. \n
Accessories and decor\n
High-tech style interiors have no use for additional decor. After all, plenty of light, chrome, and glossy surfaces
        perfectly match any interior. But if the room lacks comfort and coziness, you can use the original floor and
        table lamps, made of metal, glass, and plastic. Surrealist paintings, metal statues, original glass decor add
        extra glamour and urban chic. \n
    </string>
</resources>